<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: assets-pipeline | Sebastien Lachance]]></title>
  <link href="http://sebastienlachance.com/blog/categories/assets-pipeline/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sebastienlachance.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-29T11:40:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://sebastienlachance.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sebastien Lachance]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails Assets Pipeline and missing assets]]></title>
    <link href="http://sebastienlachance.com/blog/rails-assets-pipeline-and-missing-assets/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://sebastienlachance.com/blog/rails-assets-pipeline-and-missing-assets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I moved the entire <a href="http://www.guidedescommercesdebeauce.com">Guide des Commerces</a> from Rails 3.0.10 to Rails 3.2.3. I have to admit it, I was afraid of the assets pipeline and my first deployment attempt resulted in a lost afternoon and a bad case of stress. I had to revert back and lose some customer data (just my associate data).</p>

<p>The problem was that I tried to use the assets pipeline for half the application and let everything in the public folder for the second half (admin part). I'm pretty sure it is possible.</p>

<p>Now everything is moved and I am actually quite happy. One css and one js per page is finally a dream came true.</p>

<p>Anyway, what I really wanted to talk here is about one of the problems I had. When calling the assets precompile rake task, one compiled css file was missing. Like one of the manifest wasn't read or executed.</p>

<p>When you have multiple manifest files (not called application.css or application.js), you actually have to tell which additionnal one to precompile.</p>

<p><code>ruby config/application.rb
config.assets.precompile += ['administration.js', 'administration.css' ]
</code></p>

<h2>One gotcha with scss manifest:</h2>

<p><strong>If you are using scss files as manifests</strong>, you need to use the compiled version.</p>

<p>Like this:</p>

<p><code>ruby config/application.rb
config.assets.precompile += ['application.css' ] # this will work for application.css.scss
</code></p>

<p>Instead of:</p>

<p><code>ruby config/application.rb
 config.assets.precompile += ['application.css.scss' ]  # this will not work, but no error will be thrown
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
