<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: backbone | Sebastien Lachance]]></title>
  <link href="http://sebastienlachance.com/blog/categories/backbone/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sebastienlachance.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-10T07:53:42-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://sebastienlachance.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sebastien Lachance]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Completely unrealistic example - A Backbone Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://sebastienlachance.com/blog/completely-unrealistic-example-a-backbone-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-10T06:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://sebastienlachance.com/blog/completely-unrealistic-example-a-backbone-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, while I was playing and coding on my Backbone blog project (<a href="https://github.com/sebastienlachance/backbone-rails-blog">backbone-rails-blog</a>), I started wondering if it was something I could use to replace this blog, since I put so much time on it lately. But at the same time I kept telling myself, <strong>is Google going to index the content?</strong> The short answer is: <strong>NO</strong>, not now anyway.</p>

<p>The long answer goes like this: Facebook comments are indexed. So there should be a way to provide this content to GoogleBot. I have done my homework and this document, <a href="https://developers.google.com/webmasters/ajax-crawling/docs/getting-started">Making Ajax Applications Crawlable</a>) provides some answers. Basically, we need the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shebang_(Unix">hashbang</a>) url format. This is achieved with Backbone when we are not using pushstate.</p>

<p>Hashbang url:</p>

<pre><code>http://sebastienlachance.com#!blog-post
</code></pre>

<p>My urls:</p>

<pre><code>http://sebastienlachacne.com/blog-post
</code></pre>

<p>And frankly, I will not pursue this path. In my case anyway, it provides no real advantages to have an Ajax-powered blog.</p>

<p>In fact, I could have left Backbone and only use it on the admin backend, but as a learning tool, I didn't want to revert back (and there is so much great blogging platform now anyway).</p>

<p>Do you have any other web apps ideas (other than a todo list or blog)? In my next iteration (that is, the next app), I will be using Backbone with NodeJs and MongoDB. Sounds fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Help needed, A Backbone blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://sebastienlachance.com/blog/help-needed-a-backbone-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T12:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://sebastienlachance.com/blog/help-needed-a-backbone-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm currently doing my best to learn Backbone and his best practices. I have set up a demo blog application on GitHub (<a href="https://github.com/sebastienlachance/backbone-rails-blog">Backbone-rails-blog</a>).</p>

<p>So, if you are interested to give me some feedback, tips or check out the development progress, just watch the project to see where things are going and I'll blog the important parts as I move forward.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
